# **Matthew Cullen**

Penfield, New York, 14526 | 585-831-0531| m23.cullen@gmail.com Github | Blog | Linkedin | Portfolio

#### **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

Software Engineer with team leadership experience, an eye for detail and passion for creating beautiful responsive web pages. Loves learning, quick to understand and apply new concepts, collaborative and highly creative. Works well under pressure and adapts to change easily. Community oriented. Currently loving learning Korean and game development.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby on Rails | JavaScript | Python | HTML5/CSS | Git | SQL/NoSQL | Linux | Node | ReactJs | React Native

## **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School 09/ 2019 - 03/2020

Full Stack Software Engineering Remote Learning Program Course Report's Bootcamps: Ranked #1 for 2019-2020

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Avybe, Software Engineer Intern Website | Linkedin

10/2020 - current

- Turned designs into functional React Native components
- Worked with senior engineers on new features and code reviews
- Worked on a large code base with many talented developers

Harbec, Quality assurance team leader

Ontario New York 06/2011 - 02/2016

Led and managed a team of quality inspectors

#### **PROJECTS**

### Chat App Github | Deployed with Firebase

A way for people to chat in private or public user created channels

### **Technology Used**

- Google Firebase Realtime Database made it easy to structure my data and provide functions to listen to changes being made to the NoSql collections.
- To save time I chose to use React/Redux with HTML5/CSS/Semantic-UI as my frontend

#### Pet Assistant Frontend Backend

This was my first time using a React/Redux and I wanted to help people who care for animals so I created a way to keep track of important information about your pets simply and quickly

### **Technology Used**

- JavaScript, React/Redux, HTML/CSS (frontend)
- Ruby/Rails, Sqlite3 (backend)

#### Node.js Login/Auth service Github

A login and authentication service built with Node/Express/Mongodb Atlas.

#### **Technology Used**

- JavaScript, NodeJS, ExpressJS
- MongoDB Atlas

### **VOLUNTEER WORK**

Refuge Recovery Rochester, Web developer

 Create, deploy and maintain an informational web page for local buddhist community group 06/2018 - 08/2020